Guide to the Cased Image File 1840-ongoing PR 12
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series II: Daguerreotype, 2
  - Unidentified Female [Cathan, L.], [1843-1850] (Item 2-151)
    Female figure wearing dark dress with black ribbon at neck, brooch, white lace collar, hair parted in middle, bun in back, earrings, 1/4 profile view.
  - Unidentified Female [Cathan, L.], [1843-1850] (Item 2-152)
    Female figure wearing white bonnet, dark dress, brooch.
  - Mrs. Thomas Soden Henry (Emile Aglae Cox) (Item 2-153)
    3/4-length portrait of female figure, front view, seated with right arm resting on table, wearing brooch, earrings and rings.
  - Joseph Henry Edgerly, 1849/10/30 (Item 2-154)
    Male figure, front view, clean-shaven, wearing white shirt and dark bow tie.
    Case is in Amanda Edgerly.
  - Thomas Edgerly (Item 2-155)
    Male figure, front view, wearing white shirt, bow tie, and beard under chin.
    Sitter landing in New York from England on April 15th, 1821.
  - Unidentified Male Gilder Family Member or Friend (Item 2-156)
    Male figure, front view, bearded, moustache, wearing black jacket with dark vest, black bow tie, white shirt and high white collar.
  - Dr. Nathan Sturgis Jarvis or Unidentified Male Jarvis Family Member or Friend (Item 2-157)
    Male figure, front view, clean shaven, wearing military uniform, arms crossed in front of waist.
  - Unidentified Male Cobbler, 1850/00/00 ca. (Item 2-158)
    Male figure seated profile, wearing black vest with white shirt, sleeves rolled up past elbow, hat, plaid neckerchief, hammer in his left hand, half leather apron, head turned towards camera, holding what appears to be a boot between knees.
  - Abby Pinney Smith [Anson, Rufus], [1851-1867] (Item 2-159)
    Female figure, seated, front view, hair parted in middle, white collar and cuffs, brooch, dark dress.
  - Thomas Smith (Item 2-160)
    Male figure, head turned slightly to right, clean shaven, 3/4 length, high white collar, black bow tie, left hand on table, seated, right hand on lap.
  - Martha E. Knox and Child (Unidentified Knox Family Member or Friend) (Item 2-161)
    Female figure seated wearing white collar with brooch, hair parted in middle, front view, her right arm across waist, left arm around child seated to her left; Young girl wearing dark dress with necklace, head slightly tilted, arms at waist.
  - Unidentified Male and Unidentified Female (Item 2-162)
    Male figure seated on left, female figure seated on right wearing brooch, hair parted in middle.
  - Unidentified Female (Item 2-163)
    Female figure seated, front view, with her right arm on armrest, wearing black dress with thin white collar and cuffs, brooch, necklace, hair in tight curls on side of head hanging down to shoulder.
  - Unidentified Young Female (Item 2-164)
    Young girls seated wearing plaid off the shoulder dress, her right hand resting on lap, front view, 3/4 length.
  - Unidentified Female and Unidentified Young Female (Item 2-165)
    Female figure seated wearing white bonnet with white lace ties, dark dress, ring, brooch, hands on lap, her left hand pointer finger held by young girl standing to her left, young girl wearing checked dress, her left hand around her waist, hair in curls a
  - 2 Unidentified Females (Item 2-166)
    2 Female figures seated, female on left wearing patterned dress with white collar, brooch, hair parted in middle, holding what appears to be a book or purse with her right hand on lap, female on right wearing plaid dress with white collar and brooch, hand
  - Unidentified Female (Item 2-167)
    Female figure, front view, seated with hands holding stomach, wearing dark dress with white collar and brooch, hair in white bonnet with small ties at neck, necklace, wrinkles on face.
  - Unidentified Female (Item 2-168)
    Female figure, front view, vignette, white background, wearing floral patterned blouse with white collar, white snood, light colored bow at neck, buttons down front, 1/4 length.
  - Unidentified Young Female (Post-mortem) (Item 2-169)
    Young child laying on white pillow, wearing checked off the shoulder dress, partially covered by blanket, eyes closed.
  - 2 Unidentified Females (Item 2-170)
    2 seated female figures, female on left wearing dark dress with patterned bow at neck, what appears to be a handkerchief in her lap, hair parted in middle and sculpted over ears, female on left arm in arm with female on right, wearing black dress with whi
  - James Raymond (Item 2-171)
    Young male figure wearing black jacket and vest, white shirt, black bow-tie, white collar (down), hair parted on side, 1/2 length.
  - Martha Lyon Zabriskie (Item 2-172)
    Young girl seated, full length, hands on lap, wearing white collar and cuffs, blouse buttoned up front with piping on edges.
    Sitter is mother of George A. Zabriskie.
  - 2 Unidentified Young Female Webb Family Members or Friends with Dog (Item 2-173)
    Two young girls seated on couch with black dog, older girl is sitting straight up, wearing plaid dress, hair shoulder-length in corkscrew curls, younger girl is leaning on older girl, wearing light colored dress, hair shoulder-length in corkscrew curls, l
  - 2 Unidentified Young Female Webb Family Members or Friends [Cathan], [1843-1850] (Item 2-174)
    Young girl seated holding purse, wearing white off-the-shoulder dress with blue ribbon at sleeve, white socks, black shoes, hair parted in middle with curls to shoulder, young girl standing with right hand touching purse, wearing dark off-the-shoulder sho
  - Unidentified Male Webb Family Member or Friend (Item 2-175)
    Male figure, turned 1/4 to his right, wearing tree patterned vest, dark jacket and bow tie, white shirt, hair parted on side.
  - Unidentified Male Webb Family Member or Friend [Cathan], [1843-1850] (Item 2-176)
    Male figure, front view, hair parted on side, wearing gray vest, black jacket and bow tie, white shirt and high white collar.
  - Unidentified Male Webb Family Member or Friend (Item 2-177)
    Male figure wearing scarf at neck, black vest with one button undone, black jacket, hair parted on side, white collar and shirt.
  - Unidentified Male Webb Family Member or Friend (Item 2-178)
    Male figure wearing black foulard and jacket, white shirt with high white collar, black silk vest, full front view.
  - Unidentified Female Webb Family Member or Friend (Item 2-179)
    Female figure seated front view, wearing ribbon and brooch at neck, white lace collar, black dress, hair parted in middle.
  - Unidentified Female Webb Family Member or Friend (Item 2-180)
    Female figure seated, wearing earrings, decorative material at neck, white collar, vertically striped dress, hair parted in middle.
  - Alexander McWhorter (Item 2-181)
    Male figure wearing eyeglasses, clean shaven, high white collar, black cravat, front view, hair down back of head over ears.
    Tag inscribed "#12." attached.
  - Dr. Nathan Sturgis Jarvis or Unidentified Male Jarvis Family Member or Friend (Item 2-182)
    Male figure wearing eyeglasses, clean shaven, wearing military uniform, holding sword in right hand, sword facing to floor, seated, right elbows on table.
  - Unidentified Female (Item 2-183)
    Female figure, front view, wearing striped dark dress with floral bow-tie, white lace collar, hair in curls and pulled back, hands on lap, 1/2 length, seated.
  - 2 Unidentified Females (Item 2-184)
    2 Female figure, front view, seated, female on left holding handkerchief in her right hand on lap, her left arm around other female, both wearing dark dresses with brooches and white bows at collar, hair parted in middle, white cuffs.
  - Mrs. Mortimer Turner (Helen Davidson) and Unidentified Young Female Pintard Family Member or Friend (Item 2-185)
    Female figure and child in her lap, front view, seated, adult wearing dark dress without collar, child wearing dress that ends just below knee length.
    Turner is daughter of Eliza Pintard and Dr. Richardson Davidon, stating also: "This picture was injured during the Civil War."
  - Jane Stevenson MacLaren (Item 2-186)
    Female figure, seated with left elbow leaning on table, white collar, brooch, hairnet, fringes on black dress.
    Card catalog states that sitter is wife of Rev. Donald MacLaren.
  - Sarah Brinkerhoff (Item 2-188)
    3/4 length portrait of a seated female wearing white collar and earring in left ear, as well as a ruffled-looking dress and possible holding a handkerchief.
  - Aaron Betts Belknap (Item 2-189)
    Portrait of male figure (bust) in white shirt, solid foulard, hair over ears and parted on side.
  - Mrs. Aaron Betts Belknap [Gurney, Jeremiah], [ca1839-1871] (Item 2-190)
    Portrait of female figure (bust) with hair in curls on sides of head, white blouse and plaid scarf.
  - Charles T. Brigden and John M. Pace (Item 2-191)
    Two male figures, 3/4-length; Brigden is young boy standing on right; Pace is seated on left.
  - George Brigden, John Brigden, and Benjamin Brigden [Painted Post], 1850/00/00 (Item 2-192)
    Three young boys, 3/4-length, two standing and one seated.
    Note at rear of frame states date and location of photographer's studio.
  - William Cullen Bryant (Item 2-193)
    Male figure, profile view, wearing white collar and shirt, black tie, dark coat, sideburns.
  - Mrs. S. H. Whitlock and Willie Whitlock [Beckers & Piard] (Item 2-194)
    Female figure, front view, wearing black dress, hair parted in middle, holding infant dressed in white dress, shawl and hat.
  - Abram Stevens Hewitt (Item 2-195)
    Male figure, seated wearing white shirt, black bow tie, checked vest, beard.
  - Unidentified Male Constant Family Member or Friend (Item 2-196)
    Male figure with curly hair and beard on sides of face and under chin, wearing dark colored tie and white shirt.
  - Unidentified Infant (Item 2-197)
    Infant (female?), front view, wearing white gown, partially off the shoulder, bow at shoulder, left hand holding arm of chair.
  - Testimonial Presented to John B. Newman, 1853/01/09 ca. (Item 2-198)
    Verso of image is inscription: "This testimonial is presented to John B. Newman, M.D.L.L.W. by unanimous vote of the Trustees of Harrodsburg Female College to express great regret at his departure and high regard for his ability and distinguished service
  - Eliza H. Scott (Item 2-199)
    Young girl, front view, 1/4 length, curly bangs, light colored dress, head slightly tilted.
  - Unidentified Female and Unidentified Young Female (Item 2-200)
    Female figure seated wearing dark dress with brooch, white cuffs and collar, bow at collar, hair short to ears, holding young girl on lap, girl wearing red dress with boots and white socks, hair parted in middle to neck, hands clasped at chest.
  - Unidentified Male Harper Family Member [Thompson, Josiah W.], [ca1851-ca1860] (Item 2-201)
    Male figure, front view, right arm leaning on table, beard under chin, sideburns, chain in jacket.
  - Unidentified Young Male and Female Bailey Family Members or Friends (Item 2-202)
    3/4-length double portrait of young standing male and young seated female holding hands.
  - Unidentified Male (Item 2-203)
    Male figure, front view, seated with his right arm resting on book on table, wearing black jacket, light colored vest, black neckerchief, white cuffs and high white collar, hair parted on side and long to ears, legs crossed, light colored corduroy-like pa
  - John Smith Tooper (Item 2-204)
    Male figure, bearded, front view, wearing high white collar, white shirt, bow tie, white vest, sculpted hairstyle.
  - Alfred Perego (Item 2-205)
    Male figure, front view, white skirt, black bow tie, clean-shaven, cross on chain in vest.
    Note in case states that sitter is brother of Joseph Perego.
  - Olin S. Fleet [Plumbe, John, Jr., 1809-1857] (Item 2-206)
    Male figure, bearded, wearing white shirt and bow tie with high white collar.
    Sitter is grandfather of Lathrop C. Harper and husband of Margaret M. Harper, who is the daughter of Samuel B. Harper.
  - Isabella Cooper Pilcher [Weston] (Item 2-207)
    Female figure, seated with right elbow resting on book on table, fingers of right hand touching hair, which is in curls on sides of head, wearing plaid dress.
    Sitter is third daughter of Henry and Frances (Pillow) Pilcher.
  - Mrs. William Polk [Anson, Rufus], [1851-1867] (Item 2-208)
    Female figure, seated, front view, hair parted in middle, wearing white collar and cuffs, dress buttoned up front, hands on lap.
  - Unidentified Female DeGroot Family Member or Friend and 3 Unidentified Young Female DeGroot Family Members or Friends (Item 2-209)
    L-R: Young Girl seated with hands on lap, wearing blue short-sleeved dress with white stockings and black shoes with bows at ankles, bracelet on right arm, hair in braids; Adult female figure with her right arm around seated girl, wearing dark dress with
  - George Arculanius [Plumbe, John, Jr., 1809-1857], ca1856/00/00 (?) (Item 2-210)
    Male figure, front view, clean-shaven, wearing white collar, dark foulard, double breasted vest with buttons down front.
    Sitter is brother of Christina G. Arcularius (Mrs. Samuel B. Harper).
  - John Smith Tooper [Insley, Henry E.], [ca1844-ca1860] (Item 2-211)
    Male figure, front view, bearded, wearing gloves, hat, double breasted coat, kerchief, black muffler, tall black hat.
  - Christina Arcularius Harper [Thompson, Josiah W.], [ca1851-ca1860] (Item 2-212)
    6 month old infant wearing white gown with pink bows at shoulders, hands clasped off to sitters right.
    Sitter is "oldest sister of L.C. Harper" and "daughter of J.P. Harper".
  - Mary A. Sackett (Mrs. Bradford) (Item 2-213)
    Female figure seated with right hand on table, 3/4-profile, wearing earrings and long chain dangling down front of dark dress.
    Sitter is daughter of Wm. H. Sackett and Amanda Harper Sackett, who is the daughter of Samuel B. Harper.
  - Harrison Blake II [White, E.] (Item 2-214)
    Portrait of male figure, 3/4 length with high white collar, solid foulard, hair on sides of face and over ears
    Inside case: Made by William Shew, corner of Court & Howard Sts. Boston; Husband of Susan C. Blake of New Brunswick, NJ.
  - Herman Blenerhasset (Item 2-215)
    Daguerreotype of a painting--male figure (bust) in frame wearing white scarf, half front profile.
    Inside beneath plate: "This is a portrait of Herman Blenerhasset of Burr fame, a piece from a miniature many years now since lost OCT 1885/ J.E. Stillwell MD/ 150 E 21st NY"
  - Elizabeth Van Schoonhoven Crosby (Mrs. Edward Nicoll Crosby) (Item 2-216)
    Portrait of a female, front view, wearing earrings, white collar with bow, and striped dress.
    Enclosed note states that sitter is mother of Frederic Van Schoonhaven Crosby and grandmother of donor.
  - Unidentified Female and 2 Young Female Greenwood Family Members or Friends (Item 2-217)
    Three female figures, adult in middle, wearing plaid shawl and white collar, arms around shortest girl who is wearing plaid dress.
  - Unidentified Female and Young Female Low Family Members or Friends [Williamson, Charles H], [ca1844-1885] (Item 2-218)
    Female figure seated wearing white lace collar, dark blouse, chain, floral patterned skirt, sitter's left hand on lap and right arm around seated young female figure wearing plaid dress with white scalloped collar and hair parted in middle.
  - Unidentified Female (Barber's Wife) (Item 2-219)
    Female figure, front view, wearing white headpiece, hair in curls to shoulders, wearing dark dress with white lace collar, brooch, necklace, rings, seated with her right hand resting on table, left hand holding small book on lap.
    Sitter is identified as "Barber's Wife".
  - Unidentified Male (Item 2-220)
    Male figure, front view, wearing tall black top hat, black jacket with large buttons, bow tie, white shirt and high white collar turned down, plaid vest, half-length, clean shaven.
  - Unidentified Male (Item 2-221)
    Male figure, front view, looking to left of camera, wearing black jacket and vest, black tie, white shirt with high white collar turned up, hair parted in middle, clean-shaven.
  - Unidentified Male (Item 2-222)
    Male figure with full beard under chin, hair parted on side and curly, wearing black jacket and vest, white shirt, black bow-tie at neck.
  - Unidentified Young Female Greenwood Family Member or Friend [Lawrence] (Item 2-223)
    Young girl standing, right elbow leaning on adjacent table, clasped hands, full length, wearing white pantaloons, and plaid jumper with plaid/patterned shirt underneath.
  - William Whitlock [Beckers & Piard] (Item 2-224)
    Young boy wearing dark colored dress with blue piping, buttons down front, white collar, standing with his right hand leaning on table, front view, full length.
  - Henry Pilcher [Weston] (Item 2-225)
    Male figure, front view, sideburns, high white collar, black bow tie, white shirt, slightly reclined, left arm resting on table, seated.
  - Charles W. Troughton and Mrs.Troughton [Thwaite] (Item 2-226)
    Adult female figure seated with child on lap, female wearing white hat, brooch, earrings, bracelet, necklace/chain, rings, white collar and sleeves, black dress, child wearing checked dress with bow at shoulder, ring, white pantaloons.
    Sitters are mother and son; Charles is husband of donor.
  - Unidentified Male (Item 2-227)
    Male figure, 1/4 profile view, curly white hair long to neck, wearing white shirt with black jacket and bow tie, half length.
  - Unidentified Female (Item 2-228)
    Female figure wearing polka dot dress, seated, hair parted in middle, white collar and cuffs, arms crossed over stomach, what appears to be a basket of flowers on adjacent table.
  - Unidentified Female (Item 2-229)
    Female figure, bust, wearing dark dress with black bow at neck, white collar, hair parted in middle, vignette.
  - Unidentified Male [L.B.B. & Co.], 1840/00/00-ca1842/00/00 (Item 2-230)
    Male figure, front view, seated with his right arm resting on table, left hand on lap, wearing striped vest with white shirt, neckerchief, dark jacket, hair long and parted on side, beard under chin.
  - John Beekman (Item 2-231)
    3/4-length portrait of male figure with white hair, high white collar and scarf-like necktie
    2 Copies; Accompanying note enclosed describes sitter's history; Father of Wm. Fenwick Beekman, son of James Beekman; Daguerreotype of miniature, came from Mrs. Secore of White Plains in 1948.
  - Mrs. John Beekman (Mary Elizabeth Bedlow) (Item 2-232)
    Portrait of female figure (bust) wearing lace bonnet and lace collar
    2 Copies; Accompanying note enclosed describes sitter's history; Mother of Wm. Fenwick Beekman; Daguerreotype of miniature, came from Mrs. Secore of White Plains in 1948.
  - Frances (Pillow) Pilcher [Weston] (Item 2-233)
    Female figure, seated holding book in left hand, wearing fringed shawl around shoulders, white bonnet with sash and bow under chin, left arm resting on table.
    Sitter is wife of Henry Pilcher.
  - George T. Bliss (Item 2-234)
    Full-length portrait of seated, infant male with dress off the shoulder, plaid type midriff, hands on lap, barefooted.
    Newspaper below plate.
  - Maria Abernathy Burr [Anson, Rufus], [1851-1867] (Item 2-235)
    3/4-length portrait of a seated young girl with curls on either side of her head, hands on lap, checked dress, and left elbow on a table.
    Enclosed note states that sitter is daughter of Melanthore Burr and Euphemia Cooper Burr; mat is stamped with "ANSON 589 Broadway".
  - William Cromwell (Item 2-236)
    Male figure (bust) wearing white shirt and collar/neckerchief, black jacket, sideburns.
    Sitter is grandfather of donor.
  - Unidentified Female Low Family Member or Friend (Item 2-237)
    Female figure in profile, wearing checked blouse with white neckerchief, hair in bun at back of head.
  - Unidentified Young Male Low Family Member or Friend (Item 2-238)
    Young boy standing, 3/4 length, wearing black jacket, white collar, hand in pocket, front view.
  - Maria LaGrange Elmendorf (Van Veghten) (Item 2-239)
    Female figure, front view, half-length, seated with arm resting on table, wearing lace cap and portrait brooch.
  - Madelene Fortier (1796-?) [Welling], 1850/00/00-1861/00/00 (Item 2-240)
    3/4-length female, seated with right elbow on table, wearing bonnet, hair parted in middle, hands folded on lap, brooch at neck.
    Sitter is wife of John G. Concklin.
  - Unidentified Male Gilder Family Member or Friend [Holmes, S. A. (Silas A.), 1819 or 20-1886], [1847-ca1858] (Item 2-241)
    Male figure wearing black jacket (buttoned closed) and bow tie, with white shirt and high white collar, hair parted on side, front view.
  - Unidentified Male Gilder Family Member or Friend (Item 2-242)
    Male figure wearing tall white hat with black band, black jacket and bow tie, dark vest, right elbow on table with book, sideburns.
  - Horatio Gates Shumway (Item 2-243)
    Male figure, front view, wearing white shirt, black bow tie, clean-shaven.
  - Mrs. Hopkins (Ellen Dunlap) (1857/1858-1939) [Hale] (Item 2-244)
    Female infant seated wearing polka dot dress off-the-shoulder, full length, facing front, ankles crossed.
    Sitter is the founder of The New York School of Applied Design For Women.
  - Jonathan Goldsmith Horton (Item 2-245)
    Male figure, seated, front view, clean-shaven, gray hair, wearing dark jacket, patterned vest, resting left arm on arm of chair.
  - Unidentified Female Harper Family Member [White, E.] (Item 2-246)
    Female figure, seated, front view, wearing plaid dress, left elbow leaning on table, holding flowers on lap, wearing earrings.
  - Unidentified Male Harper Family Fireman [Paret] (Item 2-247)
    Male figure, seated with left elbow on table and right hand on right thigh, wearing red shirt, brown bow tie, clean shaven, wedding band on finger.
  - Sarah Cooper Hewitt [Anson, Rufus], [1851-1867] (Item 2-248)
    Infant seated in large chair, front view, full length, right shoe missing, white gown.
  - Unidentified Young Female Hincken Family Member Holding Doll [Prosch, Miss] (Item 2-249)
    3/4-length portrait of young girl standing next to high chair with left hand holding left hand of doll in high chair, front view, doll wearing pink dress, girl wearing patterned dress with hair in corkscrew curls.
  - Dr. Nathan Sturgis Jarvis or Unidentified Jarvis Family Member or Friend (Item 2-250)
  - Unidentified Female Jarvis Family Member or Friend (Item 2-251)
    Female figure wearing white bonnet, black gloves, black coat and dress.
  - Unidentified Female Jarvis Family Member or Friend (Item 2-252)
    Female figure, front view, seated wearing white bonnet, both hands holding book on lap.
  - Unidentified Young Female (Item 2-253)
    Young girl seated on table beside chair, hands on lap, wearing plaid off the shoulder dress with black trim and buttons, hair in corkscrew curls to shoulder and parted on side.
    Another image of this unidentified girl is located in this collection.
  - Mrs. Charles White Kellogg (D. Comstock) [Gurney, Jeremiah], 1857/02/12 (Item 2-254)
    Female figure seated with her right arm resting on table, wearing brooch, white lace collar, dark dress with black lining, white cuffs, hair parted in middle.
  - Peter Comstock Kellogg [Gurney, Jeremiah], 1853/00/00 (Item 2-255)
    Young boy seated with his right arm resting on table, wearing black coat with buttons down front, white collar, light colored bow tie and pants, hair parted on side, looking off to camera's right.
  - Unidentified Male Feeding Sheep (Item 2-256)
    Male figure in foreground, standing, wearing hat, vest, white shirt, necktie, holding basket, sheep feeding from basket, flock of sheep grazing in meadow, trees in background, outdoor scene.
  - J.B. Newman Jr. (Item 2-257)